

WESTON VINCZE

Canada, ON ~ (647) 385-9870 ~ WestonVincze@gmail.com github.com/WestonVincze ~ linkedin.com/in/weston-vincze

I am a frontend web developer backed by over 5 years of professional experience. I specialize in JavaScript libraries and frameworks with a strong proficiency in React and TypeScript.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Expert

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, SQL

Advanced

GoLang, PHP, Python, Bash

Intermediate

Liquid, Java, C++, C

FRAMEWORKS/ **LIBRARIES**

Expert

React, React Hooks, NextJS, Jest, Storybook, Node, Redux, Scss, Sass, Less, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, WordPress

Advanced

GraphQL, VueJS, RxJS, XState, Spring, MaterialUI, ChakraUI, MongoDB

Intermediate

AngularJS, BabylonJS, CanJS

TOOLS/TECHNOLOGIES

Expert

Git, Rest APIs, JIRA, SEO, Dev Tools, JSON, UI/UX Design

Advanced

Webpack, AWS, Docker, Azure, LBC IT Solutions Inc. Figma, Unity

Intermediate

Kubernetes, Helm, Postman

HOBBIES

- Game Development
- Drawing & Animation
- Improv & TTRPG's
- World Building

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

01/2023 - 09/2023

Auvik

Waterloo, Canada (Remote)

Collaborated within a small agile team alongside developers, designers, and project managers. I executed tasks from minor updates, to implementing new features, to full project lifecycles.

- Contributed to Avuik's SaaS platform, emphasizing security and role management standards
- Led project to rebuild legacy payment form solution with React and enhance payment options
- Seamlessly integrated Zuora iframe into Auvik's design despite strict constraints
- Developed robust tests with reusable, modular tools for GraphQL, custom hooks, and APIs Contributed to backend APIs with GraphQL, GoLang, and Kubernetes

JAVASCRIPT CONSULTANT

11/2021 - 11/2022

Bitovi

Chicago, USA (Remote)

Worked as a developer and consultant in Bitovi's React Department for a diverse set of clients. I handled a wide spectrum of projects from short-term solo tasks to extensive agile collaborations.

- Created future-proof React solutions using TypeScript with a focus on technical excellence
- Conducted rigorous testing with Jest and leveraged Storybook to showcase UI components
- Delivered live presentations on open-source libraries like Storybook and react-to-webcomponent
- Contributed updates to open source libraries, including <u>StackStorm</u> and <u>react-to-webcomponent</u> Designed a senior-level take-home test and rubric for a client's hiring process

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

04/2020 - 11/2021

Richmond Day

Toronto, Canada (Remote)

Collaborated with project managers and designers to create and update websites for a diverse set of clients including MINI, BMW, Rapid, and LG.

- Developed scalable, data-driven applications primarily with ASP.NET Framework
- Created interactive web components with JavaScript and customized open-source libraries
- Implemented pixel-perfect, responsive designs from PSD mockups provided by designers
- Handled deployments, migrations, and AWS database updates via SFTP

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

07/2018 - 11/2019

Toronto, Canada

Collaborated in a small development team to deliver large-scale web applications for clients.

- Developed dynamic data-driven MVC Applications using ASP.NET Core and VueJS
- Assisted in React app development for Air Canada, fetching content via API calls
- Built and launched a WordPress website for a client with a fully customized isotope.js theme

EDUCATION _

COMPUTER PROGRAMMER - DIPLOMA

09/2015 - 05/2018

Toronto, Canada

Seneca College

- Completed 8 month co-op at PWC Technologies as a Software Developer Intern
- Graduated with honors